The Erdbeben in Hihiti.
The Erdbeben in Hihiti was a black Erdbeben,
which was in 2012, in 2016,
and was in the same age as the old age.
The center of the Latin American state bridge bridge.
The Stärke of Erdbeben's Erdbeben is located 7.0 on the right of the scale.
After the research of the region, the Erdbeben is located at 200,000 people.
Many more are open and relaxed.
The Erdbeben is located at the highest level of the Erdbeben in the region,
which is more than 200 years old.
There are many times more and more plundering.
The country is trying to get out.
Many countries try to help Hiti and find her very well.
We have many more cities and techniques and have to help her.
It is very difficult now to help her.
I think it is better if it is not a long time ago,
how Hiti would go.
People are very happy.
But we are very good here and we are very happy to change this area.